Guide to the Charles Hill Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Research Materials and Subject Files
  - General
    - Negri/Unger/Bilgrami, 2014 (Box 44, Folder 20)
    - New England's Grand Strategy, 2003 (Box 44, Folder 21)
    - Nicolson - Diplomacy Protean, 2004 (Box 44, Folder 22)
    - Norman Conquest - Bayeux tapestry, 1995 (Box 44, Folder 23)
    - Notes for Weaver's Lost Art, 2013 (Box 44, Folder 24)
    - Notes on "States", 2014 August 29 (Box 44, Folder 25)
    - Notes on torture, 2014 October 20 (Box 44, Folder 26)
    - Novel, 2008 (Box 44, Folder 27)
    - Nuclear-free world, 2007–2010 (Box 44, Folder 28)
    - "On Decadence", 2012–2013 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Occupy Wall Street, 2011 October 20 (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - On Diversity, 2001–2009 (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - Patriot Act (an regarding The Federalist Papers), 2004 (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - Patriotism essay, 2009 November 14 (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Peacemaking, 1919 (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - PEN "How Does the State Imagine?" 13 January 1986 New York Public Library, 1986 January 13 (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - Penn's treaty with the Indians, 1992–1999 (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - Penelope (The Odyssey) and weaving (The Old State Secret), 2013 (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - Penn (University of Pennsylvania) Law, Philadelphia and D. C. (Washington Institute for Near East Policy), 2007 May 17 (Box 45, Folder 10)
    - Philippines, 2006 March 10 (Box 45, Folder 11)
    - Plato, Statesman (Parthenon- Panathenaen - Peplos), 1926–2000 (Box 45, Folder 12)
    - Plutarch, 1999 (Box 45, Folder 13)
    - Poetry/epic notes, 1942–1993 (Box 45, Folder 14)
    - Policy, 1989–1995 (Box 45, Folder 15)
    - Policy planning staff - photograph, 1977 (Box 45, Folder 16)
    - "Political Science", 2008 (Box 45, Folder 17)
    - Pope Benedict (Regensburg), 2006 (Box 45, Folder 18)
    - Portraits, 1984–1988 (Box 45, Folder 19)
    - Post-Ottoman map of Middle East, undated (Box 45, Folder 20)
    - Pragmatism, 1998 (Box 45, Folder 21)
    - Preemption/just war theory (Bush/Annan at United Nations General Assembly 2003), 2004 (Box 45, Folder 22)
    - Presidential address to Muslim world, 2009 February 14 (Box 45, Folder 23)
    - Presidential election, 2000 (Box 45, Folder 24)
    - Presidential memoirs, writings of…Bush, John Lewis Gaddis, Charles Hill, 2009 January (Box 45, Folder 25)
    - Profiles (lives, biography) and the Gaze (portraits and faces) (a Charles Hill book?), 2003–2009 (Box 45, Folder 26)
    - Proust, undated (Box 45, Folder 27)
    - The Quiet American, 1979–2003 (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Rand - Yale conference (Charles Hill chart), 2014 April 25 (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - Redpath - Yale Club of New York City, 2007 March 31 (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - The Regicides in Connecticut, 1994 (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - The Reindeer, 1994 (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - Robert Straus-Hupe, 2005 (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - Rome and the Parthenon, 2004 (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - Rubens (and Richelieu), 2007 (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - The Rum of Kasch, 2006–2008 (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - Ruth Barkan Marcus, 2008 (Box 46, Folder 10)
    - Sanctions ARAB-AM panel, 2010 December 1 (Box 46, Folder 11)
    - Salman Rushdie, 2007 (Box 46, Folder 12)
    - The Scarlett Letter, 1975–2004 (Box 46, Folder 13)
    - Schleswig-Holstein question, 1911–1995 (Box 46, Folder 14)
    - Science policy, 1997–1998 (Box 46, Folder 15)
    - Sermon - Charles Hill at Battell, 2006 December 3 (Box 46, Folder 16)
    - Shabbtai Sevi - Cotton Mather, 2006–2007 (Box 46, Folder 17)
    - Socrates: When to do Nothing, undated (Box 46, Folder 18)
    - Spratley's, 1999–2001 (Box 46, Folder 19)
    - The State, 2001–2002 (Box 46, Folder 20)
    - Statecraft notes, 1993–1994 (Box 46, Folder 21)
    - The Study of War, 2014 (Box 46, Folder 22)
    - T. E. Lawrence and Moby Dick "The Waste Land in the Seven Pillars of Wisdom", 1991 (Box 46, Folder 23)
    - Technology (United States Institute of Peace), 1994 April 28 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Telos, 1999–2013 (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Terrorism, 2014–2016 (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Theory of everything, 1994 (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Thomas Piketty, 2014 (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Titles, 2000 (Box 47, Folder 6)
    - Truth, 1996–1999 (Box 47, Folder 7)
    - Ukraine, 2004–2005 (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - The United Nations and the Middle Earth, 2002 (Box 47, Folder 9)
    - UN (United Nations) exercises - The Press Club, 1993 (Box 47, Folder 10)
    - UN (United Nations): We Saved it: Now What?, 2003 October (Box 47, Folder 11)
    - "Universals" (with materials on the Pope's UN speech), 1991 (Box 47, Folder 12)
    - UR thinkers, 1995 (Box 47, Folder 13)
    - U.S. (United States) China 1982 communique (Box 47, Folder 14)
    - Vietnam & Kissinger (Charles Hill notebook), 1972–1973 (Box 47, Folder 15)
    - Vietnam - "Black Flight Suits and White Ao-Dais", undated (Box 47, Folder 16)
    - Vietnam - "The Missing Years", 1989–2007 (Box 47, Folder 17)
    - Vietnam - 30th anniversary of the fall of Saigon panel, 2005 (Box 47, Folder 18)
    - Vietnam casualty figures, 2000 April 18 (Box 47, Folder 19)
    - Vietnam - Charles Hill "oral history", undated (Box 47, Folder 20)
    - Vietnam - missing years, Charles Hill letter on McNamara book, 1995 (Box 47, Folder 21)
    - Wall Street Journal interview, 2012 (Box 47, Folder 22)
    - Wallenstein, 2003–2006 (Box 47, Folder 23)
    - Warrior - Scholar Project Sun Tzu, 2012–2016 (Box 47, Folder 24)
    - WF "Hot Coffee, Hot Issues" Charles Hill on Iraq (September 2007) (Petraeus report next week) (Box 47, Folder 25)
    - When to do Nothing Minh, Fabius, Kuthzov, Socrates, et alia, Undated (Box 47, Folder 26)
    - World Order - Middle East, 2013 (Box 47, Folder 27)
    - World Order - China, 2011 (Box 47, Folder 28)
    - Yale, 1997–2006 (Box 47, Folder 29)
    - Yale anecdotes, Undated (Box 47, Folder 30)
    - Yale Club of New Haven, 2013 December 2 (Box 47, Folder 31)
    - Yale Model Congress, 2007 November 9 (Box 47, Folder 32)
    - Yoknapataupha quote (Yardley)/The Bear/Faulkner's fictive architecture, 1997–2005 (Box 47, Folder 33)
    - The Zeusiad, 1997–2005 (Box 47, Folder 34)
    - Zionism, 1998–2003 (Box 47, Folder 35)
  - Background on book Grand Strategies
    - Angling: Walton, Thoreau, 2005 (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Bibliography, 2007 (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - Churchill, "The River War", Undated (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - Civilization (Rome) theme, 1935–2005 (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - Declaration of Independence - a global history, 2007 (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - Don Quixote; Case of Montecinos - notes, 2008 (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - Eliot, Daniel Deronda, 2005 (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - Emma Bovary's reading, 2005 (Box 48, Folder 8)
    - Epics Auden New Year Letter, Undated (Box 48, Folder 9)
    - Epics of statecraft (illustrations), 2005 (Box 48, Folder 10)
    - Malraux, The Human Condition, 2004 (Box 48, Folder 11)
    - Malraux, The Human Condition (Man's Estate), 1963–2004 (Box 48, Folder 12)
    - Pen and Sword - oratory speeches, 1897–2005 (Box 48, Folder 13)
    - Plato, Gorgias, 1983–2003 (Box 48, Folder 14)
    - Pope and the Polis, Undated (Box 48, Folder 15)
    - Readers good and bad, 2008 (Box 48, Folder 16)
    - Reading lists and progress on book, 2006 (Box 48, Folder 17)
    - Robinson Crusoe, Undated (Box 48, Folder 18)
    - Rousseau at the Venice Embassy, 1966–1991 (Box 48, Folder 19)
    - Short biographies, Undated (Box 48, Folder 20)
    - Social Contract/State of Nature/Descent to Hades, 2004 (Box 48, Folder 21)
    - Thomas Mann Magic Mountain, 2005–2007 (Box 48, Folder 22)
    - Treaty of Westphalia 1648, 1991–2005 (Box 48, Folder 23)
    - Venetian diplomacy, Undated (Box 48, Folder 24)
  - Directed Studies
    - Accountability, 1998–2001 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Bob Dahl: lectures on democracy and the Constitution, 2000 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Bulldog Days, 1999 (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - Burke (articles), 1998–2000 (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Charles Hill on the international system in danger, 1996 April 21 (Box 49, Folder 5)
    - Charles Hill radio interviews, 1999 (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - David Witts, 2001–2002 (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - Divinity, 1993–1996 (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - Emerson, 1985–1987 (Box 49, Folder 9)
    - Emerson and Stein, Plato and Socrates, 1997 (Box 49, Folder 10)
    - Goethe, Iphigenia and Tauris, 1942–2002 (Box 49, Folder 11)
    - GS (Grand Strategy) Decline and Fall of the Roman Empire, 1956–1993 (Box 49, Folder 12)
    - GS (Grand Strategy): teaching Grand Strategy (core elements), 1999 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - GS (Grand Strategy) Theory and Practice, 2000 June 23 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Harvard rap, 2002 (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - "Hercules's New Labors", 2001 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Hiawatha Longfellow, 2003 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - John Dewey, 1969–1997 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - IS (International System)- Fashuda - Africa, 1898–1997 (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - "Love and War: a Sea-Reading Odyssey", 2002 (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - Love and War: Readings at Sea on Civilization's Great Theme, 1943–2002 (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - Machiavelli articles, 1958–2001 (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Mexico/Canada/NAFTA, 1914–1994 (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Nitze "Complementary", 1960 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Nori's book, 1985–1998 (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Persian Wars, 1932–1989 (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Post modernism (How to speak…), 2000 (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - "Queer Theory", 1996 (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - Risk analysis - why were we surprised?, 1990–2001 (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - Speech material, 1989–1997 (Box 51, Folder 9)
    - Syllabus - "The Intellectual Making of the Modern World", 2000 (Box 51, Folder 10)
    - "The Logic Chain" and correspondence with Paul Kennedy, 1994 (Box 51, Folder 11)
    - The War on Terrorism in Afghanistan 2001 (Box 51, Folder 12-13)
  - Iraq War
    - AYA (Association of Yale Alumni) U. S. foreign policy after September 11, 2002 (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Bankruptcy, 2002 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Baseball caps, 1994–2001 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Bromund, Ted, 1996 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - Canada, 2000–2003 (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - Careers, 1999–2004 (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - Coalition against IQ, 1996–1998 (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - Clippings on the Iraq War, 2002 (Box 52, Folder 8)
    - Conferences (post-war peace conferences), 2000 (Box 52, Folder 9)
    - Criticism (literary) and GS methodology, 2012 (Box 52, Folder 10)
    - Desert Storm, 1991 (Box 52, Folder 11)
    - Disease, 1997 (Box 52, Folder 12)
    - Espionage, 1994 (Box 52, Folder 13)
    - Ethics, 2000–2001 (Box 52, Folder 14)
    - Ethiopia (Fasil Amdetsion), 2004 (Box 52, Folder 15)
    - Europe (new departures), 2003–2005 (Box 52, Folder 16)
    - Hayak lecture, 1994–2002 (Box 52, Folder 17)
    - India: Philosophy, Politics, & Prospects, 1990–1995 (Box 52, Folder 18)
    - Iraq 2002 - UN resolutions (past) "preemption", 2002–2004 (Box 52, Folder 19)
    - Iraq (and Grotius), 2002 (Box 52, Folder 20)
    - Iraq: Act Now, 2002 September 2 (Box 52, Folder 21)
    - Iraq: After Victory, What? (George P. Shultz, Charles Hill, H Rowen memorandum to Bush July 2002), 2002 July (Box 52, Folder 22)
    - Iraq: history, politics, culture, undated (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Iraq: key documents, 2002 (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - Iraq: papers for talks, 2002 (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - Iraq: Saddam Hussein's game, 1998 (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - Material for Iraq talk, 2002 (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - Modernism - Islam (and Islam & modernism - the political theory of Islam), 2000 (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - Overseas bases/troop shift Bush, 2004 August 16 (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - POWs or unlawful combatants?, 2002 (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - Role of the United States after September 11? (Kennedy-Hill debate of 9 December 2001) (Box 53, Folder 9)
    - Run-up to Iraq War, 2003, 2004–2006 (Box 53, Folder 10)
    - Talks, 2002 (Box 53, Folder 11)
    - "Teach-ins" & other Iraq War talks, 2003 (Box 53, Folder 12)
    - Terrorism and the Arab-Islamic world, 2002 (Box 53, Folder 13)
    - The Bookstore, 2005 (Box 53, Folder 14)
    - The Iraq War, 2003 (Box 53, Folder 15)
    - The Irish Agreement, 1998 April (Box 53, Folder 16)
    - The Question of Being, 1977 (Box 53, Folder 17)
    - The Six-Front War (on terrorism), 2002 (Box 53, Folder 18)
    - UN (United Nations) Security Council resolution 441 on Iraq, 2002 November 8 (Box 53, Folder 19)
    - UNSCOM (United Nations Special Commission) to UNMOV (UNMOVIC--United Nations Monitoring, Verification and Inspection Commission) (Scott Ritter's 1998 assessment) (Box 53, Folder 20)
    - War on terrorism talks, 2002 (Box 53, Folder 21)
- Lectures and talks
  Series IV includes materials pertaining to Hill's lectures and talks. The talks document Hill's presentations to venues outside of Yale, while the lectures are often given by Hill at Yale, but outside of his classes. Some folders contain outlines of lectures and talks, rather than a written paper or a formal presentation. The series also includes research materials related to the subject of the lectures and talks.
  Series IV is arranged alphabetically.
  - 9/11 after Ten Years: Berkeley, 2011 September 12 (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - 2008 talks, 2009–2011 (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - ACTC (Association for Core Texts and Courses) on "Washington, D. C.", 2011 April 17 (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - ADL (Anti-Defamation League) Mearsheimer-Walt "Israel Lobby", 2007 November 14 (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - AISEC, 2008 April 12 (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - "An Original Relation to the Universe," St. Anthony Hall, 2007 April 12 (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - The Arab Awakening and the Israeli-Palestinian Conflict, 2012 January (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - Aurelian - curriculum, 2008 March 29 (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - AYA (Association of Yale Alumni) Litchfield - The Kent School, Middlebury, 2013–2016 (Box 54, Folder 9)
  - AYA (Association of Yale Alumni) Philadelphia, 2009 March 28 (Box 54, Folder 10)
  - AYA (Association of Yale Alumni) Manhattan, 2016 November 14 (Box 54, Folder 11)
  - Baylor lectures 2001 (Box 54, Folder 12)
  - Bill Buckley, Memorial Discussion noon 31 Hillhouse March 28, 2008 (Box 54, Folder 13)
  - Capelluto Memorial Lecture, Horace Mann School, 2008 May 20 (Box 54, Folder 14)
  - Ceremony for John Gaddis, Davenport College, 2006 April 6 (Box 54, Folder 15)
  - Charles Hill at Elizabethan Club, 2005 November 16 (Box 54, Folder 16)
  - Charles Hill talks, 2014 (Box 54, Folder 17)
  - Chinese and American literature, 2009 September (Box 54, Folder 18)
  - Class of '37 - 15 October 1999 (Box 54, Folder 19)
  - Class of '46 - Freedom, 2011 May 13 (Box 54, Folder 20)
  - Congregation, Miskan Israel (Hamdeu), 2012 (Box 54, Folder 21)
  - Cornell Lehigh, 2015–2016 (Box 54, Folder 22)
  - Dartmouth Phrygian Society, 2010 May 22 (Box 54, Folder 23)
  - Democracy and ideas (Charles Hill talk), 2009 (Box 54, Folder 24)
  - Diplomacy (general talk on it), 2010 (Box 54, Folder 25)
  - Directed Studies - 60th anniversary, 2006 (Box 54, Folder 26)
  - Divinity School panel 13 January 2009 (Faith memorandum to Obama) (Box 54, Folder 27)
  - Don Kagan, 2013 (Box 54, Folder 28)
  - Egypt "Revolution" (Hedgeye), 2011 February (Box 54, Folder 29)
  - Ethiopia MFA (Ministry of Foreign Affairs)- African Women, 2014–2015 (Box 54, Folder 30)
  - Farne - Betts House, reform of State Department, 2007 June (Box 54, Folder 31)
  - Federalist Society - Yale Law School, 2009 (Box 54, Folder 32)
  - Foreign policy challenges for new president ISS 7 November 2000 Colloquium (American Grand Strategy) (Box 54, Folder 33)
  - Freedom & American Exceptionalism at Hoover, 2011 July (Box 54, Folder 34)
  - Georgetown Tocqueville Forum, 2011 March (Box 54, Folder 35)
  - Gettysburg (Eisenhower Institute), 2008 September 5 (Box 54, Folder 36)
  - Gilad Shalit, 2012 October (Box 54, Folder 37)
  - Grand Strategy: an American Problem (Democracy) Indiana 2nd lecture, 2012 (Box 54, Folder 38)
  - Grand Strategic Extravaganza mini-lecture, 2003 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - Grand Strategy Kennedy vs. Hill debate on war with Iraq HGS 211, 2003 February 24 (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - GS (Grand Strategy) and the CEO, Yale School of Management, 2011–2013 (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - GS (Grand Strategy) and Yale Democrats, 2011 (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - GS (Grand Strategy) book talk, 2010 (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - GS (Grand Strategy) dedication, 2006 December 11 (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - GS (Grand Strategy) reunion - Odysseus and oar, 2007 March (Box 55, Folder 7)
  - GS (Grand Strategy) reunion, 2016 October 14 (Box 55, Folder 8)
  - GS (Grand Strategy) reunion 2007--Charles Hill on Odysseus's oar (Box 55, Folder 9)
  - Horace: lecture, 2007–2009 (Box 55, Folder 10)
  - Hoover media colloquium on the Middle East, 2013 July 15 (Box 55, Folder 11)
  - Indiana Patten lectures, 2011–2012 (Box 55, Folder 12)
  - Key talks, 2010 (Box 55, Folder 13)
  - Keynote, Model UN, 2002 January 31 (Box 55, Folder 14)
  - Lee Institute Stratford Hall (notes on slavery), 2010 May (Box 55, Folder 15)
  - Literature, statecraft, and world order - a problem for higher education (Indiana I), 2012 (Box 55, Folder 16)
  - Middlebury, 2015 October 22 (Box 55, Folder 17)
  - Naval War College, 2010 June 9 (Box 55, Folder 18)
  - Naval War College Cloisters speech, 2012 August 15 (Box 55, Folder 19)
  - Naval War College & Grand Strategy, 2010 August (Box 55, Folder 20)
  - NDU (National Defense University) class visit, Charles Hill talk, 2010 (Box 55, Folder 21)
  - Niebuhr Forum (Charles Hill credo), 2005–2006 (Box 55, Folder 22)
  - Notes for talks, 1992–1998 (Box 55, Folder 23)
  - Notes for talks, 2006–2007 (Box 55, Folder 24)
  - NSS (National Security Strategy) 2010 Charles Hill analysis NWC (Naval War College), 2010 June (Box 55, Folder 25)
  - On the Diplomat & Statesman St. Thomas More lecture, 2007 September 7 (Box 55, Folder 26)
  - Presidential campaign (rebellion causes), 2016 (Box 55, Folder 27)
  - Rivendell, 2008 October 22 (Box 55, Folder 28)
  - The Role of Religion in the Modern World - Niebuhr Forum, 2004 February 13 (Box 55, Folder 29)
  - "The Role of the U. S. in the World Today" Baylor University, 2005–2006 (Box 55, Folder 30)
  - "The Sacred and the Secular", 2002 (Box 55, Folder 31)
  - Sigma Phi Epsilon, 2005 April 9 (Box 55, Folder 32)
  - Sin (and genocide), 2010 April 13 (Box 55, Folder 33)
  - Slifka talks, 2007–2008 (Box 55, Folder 34)
  - Slifka, Freedom Symposium, 2011 (Box 55, Folder 35)
  - "Statement at the Foreign Service Institute", 2002 May (Box 55, Folder 36)
  - Stopping wars, making peace - Law School, Reisman, 2007–2008 (Box 55, Folder 37)
  - Taiwan - panel on 2008 elections, 2008 March 27 (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - Talks, 2012 (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - Teaching Grand Strategy (and learning), 2008 (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - Teaching GS (Grand Strategy) conference, 2008 September (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - Tikvah, 2012 (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - Tikvah - How to Understand an Historical Period, 2013 (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - Various lectures, 2006–2016 (Box 56, Folder 7)
  - West Point lecture - "The Labels of International Life", 2009 February 6 (Box 56, Folder 8)
  - Wheaton College lecture, 2004 November (Box 56, Folder 9)
  - Wheaton College Tiffany lecture, 2004 (Box 56, Folder 10)
  - World Fellows, 2008–2010 (Box 56, Folder 11)
  - Yale Beijing Center, video on GS (Grand Strategy), 2016 August (Box 56, Folder 12)
  - Yale Law School - Christian Law Students Association (Charles Hill talk R110), 2005 February 23 (Box 56, Folder 13)
  - Yale Women's Organization (YUWO) lectures, 2004 November (Box 56, Folder 14)
  - Zionism reconsidered, 2013 (Box 56, Folder 15)
- Writings
  Series V contains drafts of Hill's articles and books. Hill often wrote his essays by hand at first; and few of them required extensive editing before publication. Hill's "notes" contain drafts of articles, his thoughts on current events, and writing exercises. Also included are drafts of Hill's book, Grand Strategies, as well as an unpublished manuscript on Sigmund Freud entitled The Importance of Untenable Theories. The series also contains ideas and drafts of chapters for the book World Order by Henry Kissinger. There are also several files of handwritten notes, essays, and articles on various topics, but particularly on world affairs and grand strategy.
  Series V is arranged alphabetically.
  - General
    - Admission of States, 1993 (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - "America" in unwritten Freud-China-America book, 2014 (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - "America and the World" Time, written by CH for Henry Kissinger, 1975 December 9 (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - "American Foreign Policy and the Middle East", 2011 (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - "The Bear" by William Faulkner, undated (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - BP (British Petroleum) - Yale seminar on Russia - transcript, 2005 October 21 (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - Book proposal - "Governing Diversity in a Dangerous World", 2013 July 9 (Box 57, Folder 7)
    - Book proposal - "Splendid Encounters", 2006 (Box 57, Folder 8)
    - Drafts of articles for Wall Street Journal, 2015 (Box 57, Folder 9)
    - Draft of introduction to Teaching Common Sense (not used), Circa 2015 (Box 57, Folder 10)
    - Gertrude Stein - The Making of Americans, undated (Box 57, Folder 11)
    - Gertrude Stein - The Making of Americans, The Mother of Us All, 2004 (Box 57, Folder 12)
    - "Governing Diversity in a Dangerous World," draft and notes, 2015 (Box 57, Folder 13)
    - Grand Strategic Extravaganza (and Seven Years War map), 2003 (Box 57, Folder 14)
    - Henry James, The American and Franco-Prussian War, undated (Box 57, Folder 15)
    - Identification, criticism, and exchange of ideas, 1993 (Box 57, Folder 16)
    - Introduction to Fouad Ajami, Crosswinds: The Way of Saudi Arabia, 2010 (Box 57, Folder 17)
    - Introduction to Fouad Ajami, The Syrian Rebellion, 2012 (Box 57, Folder 18)
    - Jane Austen (anti-Jacobin), 2005 (Box 57, Folder 19)
    - Kissinger as memoirist, 2003 (Box 57, Folder 20)
    - Charles Hill, Master's Thesis--"The City Hall in Philadelphia, 1850-1900", 1961 (Box 57, Folder 21)
    - Notes and drafts, undated (Box 57, Folder 22)
    - Notes and drafts, 2002–2016 (Box 58, Folder 1-4)
    - Notes and drafts, 2017 (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - Notes on literature and authors, 2006 (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - The Pope and the Polis--published as "Remembering--and Defending--the International States System", undated (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - Reader Reports for Yale University Press, 2006–2007 (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - Response to "What was the West?", 2013 (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - The Return of "National Character", 2011–2012 (Box 59, Folder 6)
    - "Sledgehammers and Civilization", 2015 (Box 59, Folder 7)
    - "Sword and Shield" review, 2014 (Box 59, Folder 8)
    - Washington Irving, undated (Box 59, Folder 9)
    - Weinberger--Charles Hill op-ed, 2006 (Box 59, Folder 10)
    - Writings by others, 2011–2014 (Box 59, Folder 11)
  - Grand Strategies
    - Abstract and proposal for Grand Strategies, 2004–2006 (Box 59, Folder 12)
    - Acknowledgments - Strategic Fictions, Grand Strategies, 2009 (Box 59, Folder 13)
    - Bibliography - draft, 2009 (Box 59, Folder 14)
    - Early chapter drafts for Grand Strategies, undated (Box 59, Folder 15-16)
    - Epics/stratagems draft, 2005 December (Box 60, Folder 1-2)
    - Outline and draft, 2007 (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - Prologue and introduction (not used), 2007 (Box 60, Folder 4)
  - The Importance of Untenable Theories
    - Post-manuscript materials, 2015 (Box 60, Folder 5)
    - Summary of the argument, 2015 (Box 60, Folder 6)
    - Unpublished manuscript on Freud, 2016 (Box 60, Folder 7-8)
  - World Order
    - Additional considerations for conclusion, 2013 September 10 (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - Afterword, 2014 May 1 (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - Conclusion, 2013 (Box 61, Folder 3)